(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-03T05:58:30.585288",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いきなり歌い始めてごめんね
Sorry for starting to sing so suddenly,
ちょっとだけそのままで聞いててね
but please listen just a little bit.
本日お伝えしたいのは
What I want to tell you today
とっても大事な君のこと！
is something very important about you!
たまにはケンカもしてきたけど
We've had our arguments sometimes,
だからこそ何でも知ってんだ
but that's why I know everything about you.
君の長所は真面目なこと
Your best quality is your earnestness,
ただ妄想癖がひどい！
but your delusional tendencies are terrible!
君が飛び降りるのならば
If you're going to jump,
僕は笑って一緒に飛び降りる
I'll laugh and jump right along with you.
止めてくれるとでも思ったか！
Did you really think I'd stop you?!
僕らの絆をみくびるか！
Do you underestimate our bond?!
そして手をつないで落ちて行こう
And let's fall hand in hand,
地面めがけてピースしよう
flashing peace signs toward the ground.
でもそういえば何かを忘れているような
But come to think of it, it feels like we forgot something...
ああそうだ！見たいテレビがあった！
Ah, right! There's a TV show I wanted to watch!
やっぱり飛ぶの後でにしませんか！
Let's postpone jumping after all!
君に出会ってからというもの
Ever since I met you...
沈むように溶けていくように
Like sinking, like melting away
二人だけの空が広がる夜に
On a night when only the two of us could see the sky
「さよなら」だけだった
It was just "Goodbye"
その一言で全てが分かった
That one word made everything clear
日が沈み出した空と君の姿
The setting sun and your figure
フェンス越しに重なっていた
Overlapped across the fence
初めて会った日から
From the day we first met
僕の心の全てを奪った
You stole everything from my heart
どこか儚い空気を纏う君は
You, who had a somewhat ephemeral aura about you
寂しい目をしていたんだ
Had lonely eyes
いつだってチックタックと鳴る世界で
In a world that ticks on and on
何回だってさ
No matter how many times
君が飛び降りるのならば僕は
If you're going to jump, then I'll jump too
君よりも先に飛び降りる
I'll jump down even before you do
説得されるとでも思ったか!
Did you think I'd try to talk you out of it?
僕の馬鹿さを侮るな!
Don't underestimate my foolishness!
え、何、あの漫画の主人公が
Hey, what is it? The protagonist of that manga
本州(ラスボス)を倒したって?
Defeated the final boss?
って何回言えばわかるんだ
I know that, because I've read it so many times!
僕は単行本派なんだ!
I'm all about the bound volumes!
ああ次が出るのいつだっけ
Ah, when does the next volume come out again?
それを読むまでは絶対許さない!
Until I read that, I will never forgive you!
いつか僕らは
Someday, we will
答え合わせするのかな
Match our answers together
そんな未来は
Such a future
忘れたままで決めたままで
I'll keep it forgotten until then
さあさあ レディース・エン・ジェントルメン
Now then, ladies and gentlemen
これよりお目にかけますわ
For your viewing pleasure is
一世一代の大舞台
A once-in-a-lifetime grand stage
長くてもどうぞごゆっくり
Long though it may be, please take your time
君が飛び降りるのならば僕は
If you're going to jump, then I'll jump too
笑って一緒に飛び降りる
Laughing, I'll jump down right along with you
止めてくれるとでも思ったか!
Did you think I'd try to stop you?
僕らの絆を見くびるか!
Look closely at the bond between us!
次に僕らが出会う世界でも
Even in the world we meet in next
またこんな風になれたらいいね
How nice it would be if it's like this again
生まれ変わったら何になるか
If we're reincarnated, what will we become?
本で占ってみようか?
Shall we try telling our fortune with books?
君は「玉ねぎ」僕は「タイヤ」
You are "Onion," and I am "Tire"
やっぱり飛ぶの今度にしませんか……?
Shall we make our next flight sooner, after all...!?
ホントのホントに飛べる日を目指して
To be able to truly, truly fly someday
もうちょっとだけ一緒に居ませんか!
Won't you stay with me just a little longer!?
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? To all you troubled souls out there
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? To those who don't fit in as humans
Be happy! 絶えず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep aiming forward without stopping
生きているんだし目を逸らした過去も
You're alive, so even the past you tried to look away from
退屈な未来もカウンセリング
And that boring future are all just counseling
やれやれ古今東西
Yare yare, from ancient times to the present, east and west
ピースピース Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead
Peace, peace! Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead!
ねぇ何だかどうして戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, what is it? I feel like we're fighting for some reason
触れられない 触れたくもない
I can't touch them, and I don't even want to touch them
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting transparent ghosts alongside my past self, self, self, self
幼くて痛い記憶の奥 残念?
A lingering memory deep inside those childish, painful days
もういないのに あれ? そっちが良い? アイロニー
Already gone? Oh? Which way is better? Irony
透かされているのは現在の自分? ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Is the current me the one being seen through? Nonsense, an unerasable label
Yes 要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい
Yes, it's a complex, like I'm being possessed
巻き付いたまま離れない 在りし日の自分
Bound tightly to the person I used to be
Undead 死んじゃいない
Undead, you're not dead yet
お前とお前の連鎖 生きていることとは
You and your chains keep on living
変わり続けることだ
Continuing to change
不不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be complacent in your misery and get satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
How cowardly not even trying to find happiness
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is one bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows if a demon or a snake will appear next?
出会って会ってやっと始まる物語
Finally encountering each other and starting our story
さ人とかばけものが 架空大ピースピース
With people, monsters, and beasts - back to the main topic
なんだかどうして未来になんぞ何の希望もない
Hey, what is it? Why do I feel like there's no hope
期待出来ないような気がして
Or expectations for the future at all?
もう随分生きている
I've already lived for quite a long time
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Dejavu and templates have given me food poisoning
素敵な出来事の気配もない
Not even a hint of anything wonderful happening
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Alas, piled-up experiences and consequences
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Mythology turned into a skeleton and boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Basically, I just want a thrill
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて整っていくガイダンス
I got bored, I got used to it, they say as guidance gets tidied up
増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されてくみたい
With increasing compliance, it's like being put under a lid
吸い尽くしてあれもこれもどれも
I've consumed it all, and this, that, and everything else
同じ味がする
All end up tasting the exact same
Undead 死んじゃいない
Undead, you're not dead yet
お前とお前の連鎖
I'm telling you, your chains and you
いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
In any era, past and future exist right now in the present
生きていることを愚直に果せよ
Fulfill what it means to be alive and honestly keep moving
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
Undead 死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
Undead, I'm telling you, you're not dead yet
幸せを諦めてしまうような人であれ
To be a person who gives up on happiness
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to the pain and enduring it
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is no different from being dead, a corpse of the undead
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? To all you troubled souls out there
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? To those who don't fit in as humans
Be happy! 絶えず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep aiming forward without stopping
生きているんだろ 目を逸らした過去も
You must be alive, even the past you tried to look away from
不幸に浸るも 幸せに浸るのも 全部全部全部お前だ
And happiness that turns to misery, all, all, all of it is you
古コン東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Ancient and modern, east and west, all combined, all creations, peace, peace!
Past & future can't change the past
Past & future run for the future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Where people gather, there are always troubles
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Survive through this story of nothing but monsters
はい、というわけでみなさんこんにちは！
Hi everyone, and welcome!
ホロライブに来て初めてのスバル……
My first time coming to Hololive as Subaru...
というわけで、大空スバル6周年記念ライブ星耀にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Subaru Oozora's 6th Anniversary Live, "Hoshiakari"!
ライブ始まる、始まる！
The live is starting, starting!
というわけで今回の配信のハッシュタグは右上のこちらになるので
So the hashtag for today's stream is right up here in the top right,
Xでいっぱいポストしてください！よろしくお願いします！
so please post a lot on X! Thank you very much!
ハッシュタグは大空スバル6周年ライブになります！はい！
The hashtag will be #OozoraSubaru6thAnniversaryLive! Yes!
なんか駆け抜けてきましたけれども、ここからまだまだライブは続きますので！
We've been running right through it, but the live is still going to continue!
ということで、次の曲はなんと、スバルの大好きなあのゲームの、あの曲を歌いたいと思います！
And for the next song, I'll sing that song from the game Subaru loves so much!
ちょっとじゃあ、場所に移動して。
Hold on, let me move to position.
よいしょよいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
はい、というわけで、それでは聴いてください。
Hi, well then, please listen.
いとしさと せつなさと 心強さと
"Koishisa to Setsunasa to Kokorozuyosa to"
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
With love, with sadness, with strength,
いつも 感じている あなたへと向かって
I always feel them, heading towards you.
あやまち人は おそられずに 進むあなたを
Without fearing mistakes, as you move forward,
涙は見せないで 見つめていたいよ
I want to watch you without showing my tears.
遠い空を あの日 眺めていた
Gazing at the distant sky that day,
やりかけの青春も 経験も そのままで
With unfinished youth and experiences just as they were,
永遠を夢見ていた あの日を今、
That day when I dreamed of eternity, now...
もう二度とくりかえさずに もどらずに 生きることが
Living without repeating it, without turning back,
できなくて あこがれて
Being unable to, yet longing for it,
でも 少しずつ 理解してきた 戦うこと！！
Yet little by little, I've come to understand: fighting!!
悲しくて 泣きたくて 叫びたくても
Even if I'm sad, want to cry, and want to scream,
あなたを 信じている 言葉にできない
I believe in you, though I can't put it into words.
あやまち人は おそられずに 進むあなたを
Without fearing mistakes, as you move forward,
涙は見せないで 信じていたいよ
I want to keep believing in you without showing my tears.
誰の目にも とまることのないまま
Passing by unnoticed by anyone's eyes,
街角のポスターは 色あせて消えていく
The posters on the street corner fade and disappear.
だけど あなたへの想いは きっと
Yet my feelings for you will surely
消えないで いつまでも 迷わずに残ってる
Not fade, remaining forever without hesitation.
偶然 でも 会えなくて
Even by chance, we can't meet,
でも世界中で1人だけは 伝えたい！！
Yet I want to tell at least one person in this world!!
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
With love, with sadness, with strength,
いつも 感じている あなたへと向かって
I always feel them, heading towards you.
あやまち人は おそられずに 進むあなたを
Without fearing mistakes, as you move forward,
涙は見せないで 見つめていたいよ
I want to watch you without showing my tears.
恋しさと せつなさと 心強さと
Heartwarming feelings, heart-wrenching feelings, and heartening feelings
いつも 感じている あなたへと向かって
Always feeling them as I head towards you
あやまちは おそれずに 進むあなたを
You, who move forward without fear of mistakes
涙は見せないで 見つめていたいよ
I want to watch over you without showing tears
遠い空を あの日眺めていた
Gazing at the distant sky that day
やりかけの青春も 経験も そのままで
Leaving unfinished youth and experiences just as they are
永遠を 夢見ていた あの日を今
Dreaming of eternity on that day once more...
ホットダック！
[Title: Hot Duck!]
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
食わず嫌いは ノンノンノン
Eating prejudices are non, non, non!
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
我は 時代の 創造児
I am the creator of this era!
いっくよ～！
Let's go~!
ホット ダック ダック グッド ラック ラック
Hot duck duck, good luck rack,
ずっと ワック ワック みん よろよろ シック シック
Always wack wack, everyone staggering sick sick,
ホット ダック ダック グッド ラック ラック
Hot duck duck, good luck rack,
ずっと ラッキー ガール これが アヒルの 輝き
Always a lucky girl, this is the duck's sparkle!
始まりました 今日のフェスティバル ズバッ!と飛び出して じゃじゃじゃじゃ～ん
Today's festival has begun, jumping out with a zoom and a ta-da~!
バズり散らした スバルドック 主人は喰わないで
Buzz-scattering Subaru Duck, master don't say "don't eat"
武士は喰わねど高楊枝 でも昼は喰わねば腹が減る
Warriors don't eat yet use a toothpick, but ducks get hungry if they don't eat
腹減った 料理の基本 さしすせそ ハイッ
I'm starving! Cooking basics: sa-shi-su-se-so, hike!
砂糖 塩 す せそうそ そ そ そ せーじ
Sugar, salt, su, se-u-so, so-so-so-sage!
ホット ダック ダック ダーダック ダック アツいビートを ズバッと ズバッと 鳴らしてけ
Hot duck duck, hot duck duck, make the hot beat ring out with a snap!
ホット ダック ダック ダーダック ダック 丸い地球を ぐるっと ぐるっと 回してけ
Hot duck duck, hot duck duck, spin the round earth all around!
水かき 汗かき ベソかき だけど スバルの努力で 一杯食わせるぜ
Webbed feet, sweating, crying, but with Subaru's effort, I'll feed you up!
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
食わず嫌いは ノンノンノン
Eating prejudices are non, non, non!
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
我は 時代の 創造児
I am the creator of this era!
ホット ダック ダック ダーダック ダック
Hot duck duck, hot duck duck,
グッド ラック ラック ずっと ワック ワック
Good luck rack, always wack wack,
みん よろよろ シック シック ホット ダック ダック
Everyone staggering sick sick, hot duck duck,
グッド ラック ラック ずっと ラッキー ガール
Good luck rack, always a lucky girl,
これが アヒルの 輝き パンチラインが 今今日も炸裂さ
This is the duck's sparkle! The punchline explodes again today!
ドカッと爆笑 けどははは 太もいとした しいぽいども 笑いに変えちゃいましょう
Roaring with laughter, but haha, let's turn clumsy mistakes into laughter!
浅い川も深く溺れ でも深くなれば骨濡れる 喋りの基本 さしすせそ ハイッ
Shallow rivers get deep and drown, but get too deep and your bones get wet. Cooking basics: sa-shi-su-se-so, hike!
さすがです! 知らなかった! すごい! センスある! そう! そう! そうせーじ
As expected! I didn't know that! Amazing! Great sense! Right! Right! Sausage!
ホット ダック ダック ダーダック ダック アツいハートを もっともっと 燃やしてけ
Hot duck duck, hot duck duck, burn that hot heart even more!
ホット ダック ダック ダーダック ダック ゆるい トークを ぐるっと ぐるっと 回してけ
Hot duck duck, hot duck duck, spin that loose talk all around!
抜け足 差し足 アヒル足 だけど ペタペタ鳴るから 居場所がバレてしまうぜ
Stealthy steps, duck steps, but they patter so your hiding spot is blown!
スバ友 アヒージョ その他 大勢も スバルの魅力で 一杯食わせるぜ
Suba-friends, ajillo, and everyone else—I'll feed you all with Subaru's charm!
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
食わず嫌いは ノンノンノン
Eating prejudices are non, non, non!
クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ クワクッ
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
我は 時代の 創造児
I am the creator of this era!
睡蓮花
[Title: Suirenka]
睡蓮の花のように 朝日に向け今日も歌う
Like a water lily blossom, I sing today facing the morning sun
睡蓮の花のように この思い水面に光る
Like a water lily blossom, these feelings shine upon the water's surface
花びらが流した涙 貴方は笑えていますか
The tears shed by the flower petals—are you able to smile?
上がりまくる季節が来た ヤバくなれるのは誰…
The season of soaring excitement has come. Who can get wild...
俺！
Me!
花びらが流した涙 あなたは笑えていますか
The tears shed by the flower petals—are you able to smile?
上がりまくる季節が来た ヤバくなれるのは誰…
The season of soaring excitement has come. Who can get wild...
俺！
Me!
ah 真夏の jamboree レゲエ 砂浜 big wave!!
Ah, midsummer's jamboree, reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
ah 悪ノリの heart beat めっちゃゴリゴリ welcome weekend
Ah, mischievous heart beat, super hardcore, welcome weekend!
ah 灼熱の jamboree 暴れまくって イイ ぜ!!
Ah, scorching hot jamboree, go wild and it's all good!!
ah 冷めないで summer dream 濡れたままで イッちゃって!!
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream, go all the way soaked wet!!
夏だぜ 夏風 夏晴れ 夏バテ
It's summer, summer breeze, summer clear skies, summer fatigue!
またコイツで決まりだ summer again
Decided with these guys again, summer again!
青く晴れた日を 笑う太陽 溢れる希望 結ぶ靴紐に期待のせて
The blue sunny day, the smiling sun, overflowing hope, tying expectations to shoelaces
風を連れて 夢の種植えるため 今走り出そう
Bringing the wind, to plant the seeds of dreams, let's start running now!
黄色いバス越え 江ノ島方面 スゲェ混み合ってる
Past the yellow bus toward Enoshima, it's insanely crowded!
ひまわり色した空への冒険 手取り合って確かな思い出残さなくちゃ
Adventure toward the sunflower-colored sky, holding hands to leave behind sure memories!
そりゃ新たな明日は輝かないから さあ笑顔に会いに行こう!!
Otherwise, tomorrow won't shine bright, so let's go meet smiles!!
睡蓮の花のように
Like a water lily flower,
日差しに向け今今日も歌う
singing towards the morning sun once again
睡蓮の花のように この思い水面に光る
Like a water lily flower, this feeling sparkles on the water's surface
花びらが流した涙 貴方は笑えていますか?
The tears shed by the petals, are you able to smile?
上りまくる季節が来た
The season that gets wild has come
ヤバくなれるのは誰… 俺!俺!俺!俺!Ole!Ole!
Who is it that can get wild... Me! Me! Me! Me! Ole! Ole!
Ah 真夏の Jamboree
Ah, Midsummer's Jamboree
レゲエ<浜辺< Big wave!!
Reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
Ah 悪ノリの Heartbeat
Ah, rough play's heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Super intense, welcome weekend
Ah 灼熱の Jamboree
Ah, scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ!!
It's fine to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
青く晴れた日を 笑う太陽
Smiling at the sun on a clear blue day
溢れる希望 むすぶ靴紐に期待のせて
Overflowing hope, tying expectations to shoelaces
風を連れて 夢の種蒔くため 今走り出そう
Bringing the wind, to plant the seeds of dreams, let's start running now
黄色いバス越え 江ノ島方面 スケゲ混み合ってる
Passing the yellow bus towards Enoshima, it's super crowded
ひまわり色した空への冒険 手取りあって
Adventure into the sky the color of sunflowers, holding hands
確かな思い出を残さなきゃそれ新たな明日は輝かないから
If we don't leave behind certain memories, then a new tomorrow won't shine
さあ笑顔に会いに行こう!!
So come on, let's go meet smiles!!
やって来たぜ イイ風 青い空
Good wind, blue sky has come
何やっててもいいんじゃね!?
No matter what you do, isn't it fine!?
そんな気分で (Yeah!!)
With that kind of mood (Yeah!!)
巨大(ぶってえ) (Yeah!!)
Huge (Damn big) (Yeah!!)
フランクフルートを 頬張りながら
Munching on a frankfurter
バナナボートで ゴールを目指す Seasonに火付く
Aiming for the goal on a banana boat, the season ignites
コケてるハイヒール の姉ちゃんを 横目に記念に「ハイ!チーズ!!」
Glancing at the girl in stumbling high heels, taking a picture for remembrance "Hi! Cheese!!"
Ah 真夏の Jamboree
Ah, Midsummer's Jamboree
レゲエ<浜辺< Big wave!!
Reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
Ah 悪ノリの Heartbeat
Ah, rough play's heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Super intense, welcome weekend
Ah 灼熱の Jamboree
Ah, scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ!!
It's fine to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
突然降り出した雨 ベッドで涙浮かべ
Sudden pouring rain, tears welling up on the bed
小せえ声で「なんで俺だけ…」
In a tiny voice "Why only me..."
待ち受けにしている写メ 変顔で思わず吹き出して
The photo on the lock screen, making a funny face and suddenly bursting into laughter
泣き言なんて言えるか「馬鹿野郎が!寂しくなんねぇ!!」
Can I say crying words like that "You idiot! I'm not lonely at all!!"
さあ自分との戦い 勝てば大切な人に会えるはずさ
Come on, if you win your battle against yourself, you should be able to meet your precious person
頑張っていればお天道様が 必ず微笑んでくれるさ
If you do your best, the sun god will surely smile upon you
もう一度君に包まれたくて
Wanting to be wrapped in you once again
走り抜けて来たよ 幾つもの季節を
I've run through so many seasons
やっと出会えた
And finally met you
Ah 真夏の Jamboree
Ah, Midsummer's Jamboree
レゲエ<浜辺< Big wave!!
Reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
Ah 悪ノリの Heartbeat
Ah, rough play's heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Super intense, welcome weekend
Ah 灼熱の Jamboree
Ah, scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ!!
It's fine to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
夏の日差しが眩しすぎて 本当の笑顔見えなくなって
The summer sunlight is too blinding, making it hard to see true smiles
空を見上げることも忘れ 地面向いて足踏みしてるんじゃねぇ!
Have you forgotten to look up at the sky, facing the ground and marking time? Don't be like that!
約束された明日なんてねぇ!! 当たり前なんて思ってるんじゃねぇ!!!!
A promised tomorrow doesn't exist!! Don't think things like that are a given!!!!
朝が迎えに来る幸せ 睡蓮とともに...
The happiness of morning coming to greet us, together with the water lily...
花びらが流した愛が あなたに届いていますか?
Has the love shed by the petals reached you?
若き小さなこの涙 笑い声になるまで...
Until these young, small tears turn into laughter...
Ah 人生という旅に出た 夫たちには後戻りはない
Ah, we who have set out on the journey called life cannot turn back
いつの日にか あの睡蓮の花のように 今まで流した涙の泉の上咲かせ
Someday, like that water lily flower, blooming above the spring of tears shed until now
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
また始まった 真裸で走り出した Season 夏は好きか?
It's started again, started running barefoot, do you like summer?
間違って交わした砂浜の Reason 付き合ってみみな
The reason of the sandy beach that crossed by mistake, try going out with it
目が合って気が合ってマジになった Season 欲望のままマンマ!!
The season where eyes met, feelings met, and it became serious, just as desire dictates!!
出会って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って
Meeting, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying...
睡蓮の花のように 日差しに向け今今日も歌う
Like a water lily flower, singing towards the morning sun once again
睡蓮の花のように この思い水面に光る
Like a water lily flower, this feeling sparkles on the water's surface
花びらが流した涙 貴方は笑えていますか?
The tears shed by the petals, are you able to smile?
上りまくる季節が来た
The season that gets wild has come
ヤバくなれるのは誰… 俺!俺!俺!俺!Ole!Ole!
Who is it that can get wild... Me! Me! Me! Me! Ole! Ole!
Ah 真夏の Jamboree
Ah, Midsummer's Jamboree
レゲエ<浜辺< Big wave!!
Reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
Ah 悪ノリの Heartbeat
Ah, rough play's heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Super intense, welcome weekend
Ah 灼熱の Jamboree
Ah, scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ!!
It's fine to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
青く晴れた日を 笑う太陽
Smiling at the sun on a clear blue day
溢れる希望 むすぶ靴紐に期待のせて
Overflowing hope, tying expectations to shoelaces
風を連れて 夢の種蒔くため 今走り出そう
Bringing the wind, to plant the seeds of dreams, let's start running now
黄色いバス越え 江ノ島方面 スケゲ混み合ってる
Passing the yellow bus towards Enoshima, it's super crowded
ひまわり色した空への冒険 手取りあって
Adventure into the sky the color of sunflowers, holding hands
確かな思い出を残さなきゃそれ新たな明日は輝かないから
If we don't leave behind certain memories, then a new tomorrow won't shine
さあ笑顔に会いに行こう!!
So come on, let's go meet smiles!!
やって来たぜ イイ風 青い空
Good wind, blue sky has come
何やっててもいいんじゃね!?
No matter what you do, isn't it fine!?
そんな気分で (Yeah!!)
With that kind of mood (Yeah!!)
巨大(ぶってえ) (Yeah!!)
Huge (Damn big) (Yeah!!)
フランクフルートを 頬張りながら
Munching on a frankfurter
バナナボートで ゴールを目指す Seasonに火付く
Aiming for the goal on a banana boat, the season ignites
コケてるハイヒール の姉ちゃんを 横目に記念に「ハイ!チーズ!!」
Glancing at the girl in stumbling high heels, taking a picture for remembrance "Hi! Cheese!!"
Ah 真夏の Jamboree
Ah, Midsummer's Jamboree
レゲエ<浜辺< Big wave!!
Reggae, sandy beach, big wave!!
Ah 悪ノリの Heartbeat
Ah, rough play's heartbeat
めっちゃゴリゴリ Welcome Weekend
Super intense, welcome weekend
Ah 灼熱の Jamboree
Ah, scorching Jamboree
暴れまくってイイぜ!!
It's fine to go wild!!
Ah 冷めないで Summer Dream
Ah, don't cool down, summer dream
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
夏の日差しが眩しすぎて 本当の笑顔見えなくなって
The summer sunlight is too blinding, making it hard to see true smiles
空を見上げることも忘れ 地面向いて足踏みしてるんじゃねぇ!
Have you forgotten to look up at the sky, facing the ground and marking time? Don't be like that!
約束された明日なんてねぇ!! 当たり前なんて思ってるんじゃねぇ!!!!
A promised tomorrow doesn't exist!! Don't think things like that are a given!!!!
朝が迎えに来る幸せ 睡蓮とともに...
The happiness of morning coming to greet us, together with the water lily...
花びらが流した愛が あなたに届いていますか?
Has the love shed by the petals reached you?
若き小さなこの涙 笑い声になるまで...
Until these young, small tears turn into laughter...
Ah 人生という旅に出た 夫たちには後戻りはない
Ah, we who have set out on the journey called life cannot turn back
いつの日にか あの睡蓮の花のように 今まで流した涙の泉の上咲かせ
Someday, like that water lily flower, blooming above the spring of tears shed until now
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
また始まった 真裸で走り出した Season 夏は好きか?
It's started again, started running barefoot, do you like summer?
間違って交わした砂浜の Reason 付き合ってみみな
The reason of the sandy beach that crossed by mistake, try going out with it
目が合って気が合ってマジになった Season 欲望のままマンマ!!
The season where eyes met, feelings met, and it became serious, just as desire dictates!!
出会って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って
Meeting, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying...
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
また始まった 真裸で走り出した Season 夏は好きか?
It's started again, started running barefoot, do you like summer?
間違って交わした砂浜の Reason 付き合ってみみな
The reason of the sandy beach that crossed by mistake, try going out with it
目が合って気が合ってマジになった Season 欲望のままマンマ!!
The season where eyes met, feelings met, and it became serious, just as desire dictates!!
出会って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って泣いて笑って
Meeting, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying, laughing, crying...
「濡れたまんまでイッちゃって!!!」
"Let's go wild while soaking wet!!!"
夏だぜ(Yeah!!) 夏風(Fuu!!) 夏晴れ(Yeah!!) 夏バテ(Boo)
It's summer!! (Yeah!!) Summer wind (Fuu!!) Summer clear skies (Yeah!!) Summer fatigue (Boo)
またコイツで決まりだ Summer Again
It's decided once again with this, summer again
はい！というわけで、
Yeah! So,
みこちとみおしゃとスバルでスイカお届けしましたー！どうだったでしょうか！
Miko, Mio, and Subaru delivered watermelons! How was it?
スイカはですね、なんとちょっとスバルが、あの沖縄でね、この3人で聞いた湘南の風がもう忘れられなさすぎて、
Subaru heard Shonan no Kaori in Okinawa with these three and couldn't forget it,
もう絶対たいってなって、ちょっとね、歌いました！みおしゃ、みこち参加してくれてありがとう！
so she definitely wanted to sing it! Mio, Miko, thanks for joining!
はい、というわけでちょっとここまでのね、振り返りをしていきたいなと思うんですけれど、
Yeah, so I'd like to look back at what we've done up to this point,
まずですね、愛おしさときつなさと心強さとではですね、スバルもう絶対に今年はストリートファイターの曲歌いたいと思ってたのでですね、このね、メンバーでねみんなでね歌えてすごい嬉しかったです！
first of all, for "Itoshisa to Setsunasa to Kokorozuyosa to", I really wanted to sing a Street Fighter song this year, so I'm so happy to sing it with everyone!
そしてですね、次にホトダックなんですけど、ま、スバルのね、折り曲をですね、お粥と私っていうこの、すご逆メンバーでね、ちょっとね歌って可愛く歌えてすごい楽しかったです！みんな参加してくれてありがとう！そして見てくれたみんなもありがとうございます！
And next is "Hot Duck"... It was so fun singing it cutely with these reverse members! Thank you everyone for participating and watching!
はい、ということでここでちょっとね、ライブステージの紹介をしたいと思います！
Yeah, so I'd like to introduce the live stage here!
なんとですね、今年のこの素敵なステージはですね、いろんなこだわりポイントが詰まってるんですけど、まずですね、えー、この後ろの、うん、くそでかモニター！これのですね、結構お気に入りです！このなんかあのサイズ感がめちゃいいです！そして、そのくそでかモニターの後ろにある、もうめちゃめちゃ綺麗なソラ！このですね、あの背景もですね結構おさらのほうもですね今後何があるかもしれないので、ぜひみんなそこにも注目してくれたらいいなっていうことでよろしくお願いします！
Can you believe this wonderful stage this year is packed with details? First, this big monitor in the back! I quite like this size feeling. And behind it is such a beautiful sky! Please keep an eye on what else might appear in the sky!
そしてですね、えーなんと今水着ということでぜひみなさんたくさんスクリーンショット撮ってください！
And since it's swimsuit season, please take lots of screenshots!
可愛いしょ！これをですね、たくさんスクリーンショットそして、えーポスト！ポストしてください！ポスト！
Cute, right? Take lots of screenshots and post them! Post!
ハッシュタグは、大空スバル6周年ライブよろしくお願いします！これ後ろとかもねすごい可愛いのでね、ぜひあんまり見る機会ないと思うので！
The hashtag is #OozoraSubaru6thAnniversaryLive! The back is also super cute, so please check it out!
はい！ポストした！ポストした！それではですね、次の拠点に行きたいと思いますので、ちょっとスバルは着替えてくるぞ！着替えてくるぞ！わー！よいしょよいしょよいしょよいしょ！
Yeah! Posted! Well then, I'm going to the next base, so Subaru is going to change clothes! Changing clothes! Heave-ho!
わあ、ということで皆さんこっからですね、まだまだライブは続きます！こっからはちょっとアイドルスバルをね、どんどん見せていきたいと思いますので、まだまだ盛り上がっていこうぜ！よろしくお願いします！
So everyone, the live continues! From here I want to show more of idol Subaru, so let's get even more hyped! Thank you!
はい！それでは次の曲聞いてください！いいですか？よし！それでは次の曲聞いてください！クリア！
Yeah! Well then, please listen to the next song! Ready? Okay! Please listen to the next song, CLEAR!
風って 鳥って
The breeze, the bird,
私より自由かな
are they freer than me?
翼がないなら 走ってくわ 行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going on!
想像とはいつも違ってる
It's always different from my imagination.
なにものか完璧 とはいかないけど
Nothing is ever quite perfect, but
心の底に 泉があるの
there is a spring at the bottom of my heart.
どんなに落ち込んでもまた 透明なもので満たされていく
No matter how depressed I get, I'm filled with transparent things again.
これって これって なんていう気持ちなの
What kind of feeling is this?
熱くて 痛くて くすぐったくて 涙が出そう
It's hot, painful, tickling, and makes me want to cry.
風って 鳥って
The breeze, the bird,
私より自由かな
are they freer than me?
翼がないなら 走ってくわ 行きたいところまで できるよね
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go. I can do it, right?
Going going going going on!
他の子にあって 私にないもの
What other girls have that I don't,
わかってはいるけど つい比べちゃうよ
I know, but I end up comparing myself.
比べちゃうよ
I always find myself comparing...
答え合わせは
Even when we check our answers,
もうしたくない
I don't want to do that anymore.
みんなと同じじゃなくても
Even if I'm not the same as everyone else,
私にできること見つけたいの
I want to find something only I can do.
夢って 愛って
What are dreams? What is love?
本当はよく知らない
Truth is, I don't really know.
どんな色 どんな形
What color? What shape?
どこからやってくるの
Where do they come from?
祈って 願って
Praying and wishing...
それだけじゃ叶わない
That alone isn't enough to make them come true.
自信がなくても始めるんだ
Even without confidence, I'll start right now.
いつかじゃなくて今できるよね
Not someday, but right now—I can do it, right?
Going, Going, Going on!
泉がここにあるの
The spring is right here,
私をつかさどるみなもとが
The source that governs who I am.
何があっても揺れたりしない
No matter what happens, it will never waver.
諦めたつもりでもまた
Even when I thought I gave up,
透明なもので満たされていく
I'm filled once again with something transparent.
これって これって
What is this feeling...?
なんていう気持ちなのだろう
What should I call it?
熱くって痛くてくすぐったくて涙が出そう
It's so hot, painful, ticklish, it makes me want to cry.
羽ばたいて 鳥って 私より自由かな
Flapping my wings like a bird, am I freer than before?
翼じゃないなら走っていくわ
If I don't have wings, I'll run instead,
行きたいところまでできるよね
All the way to where I want to go—I can do it, right?
Going, Going, Going on!
POP IN 2
[Song: POP IN 2]
ハグして どこへどこへどこへも連れてって
Hug me and take me anywhere, anywhere!
見つけて キミはキミはキミは探せるかな
Can you find me, can you, can you find me?
現れ アタシは行く先々 後々先々なら考えない
Wherever I appear, I don't think about what comes next.
ぱからぱからもびっくり溜めてばこ
Storing surprises in a sudden box,
手っ取り早くトリコになれ
Quickly become captivated!
だって 悪っつただけじゃ感じないでしょ
Because just being naughty isn't enough to feel it, right?
一瞬たりとも離れない
Never leave me, not for a single second.
I love you! ポピュよ過激にしないでね
I love you! Popiyu, don't make it too extreme.
愛現われ 結局オトりゅうだ 行く先々現れ ポピュナリュースト
Love appears, it's ultimately a sound dragon, appearing everywhere as Popinaryust.
隣ってね ポケからポピュし伸ばせポピュスぅんと繋いでね
Right by your side, stretch out from poke to pop, connect smoothly!
ポケからポピュし伸ばせポピュスぅん踏んだり蹴ったりポピュカスレモンボーイ
Poke and pop, stretch it out, through ups and downs, Popica Lemon Boy!
ポピュハッピー to you
Pop you happy to you!
ハグして 乙女乙女乙女の上飯して
Hug me, maidenly, maidenly, as a maiden's meal.
見つけ 甘く甘く甘くかき乱すの
Find it, stirring things up sweetly, sweetly, sweetly.
群がる奴らは行く先々 ラタタ歌えば列車ができちゃ
The swarming crowds wherever they go—singing Ratata makes a train!
ぱからぱからもひっくり返る予感
A hunch that even the patter-patter will turn upside down.
手っ取り早くキュートになれ
Quickly become cute!
キラキラ流る星に乗って
Riding on sparkling shooting stars,
時代を回っても一歩ずつになるし、愛はロジック
Even as eras turn, we take it step by step—love is logic.
I love you! ポピュ置いてかないでね
I love you! Popyu, don't leave me behind.
愛増し増し全力のおりゅうだ
Love increased to the max, it's full-power Oryu!
行く先々絡まれ ポピュナリューストンと繋いでね
Entangled everywhere, connect with Popinaryuston.
ポケからポピュ来るわぜポピュスぅん行ったり来たりポピュプラネーション
Pop coming from poke, pop-sund going back and forth, Poplarnation.
か・くしてどこへ どこへ どこへ も 連れってっ
To somewhere, to somewhere, to anywhere, take me
ひ・みつ デート
Secret date
キミ は キミ は キミ は 探せる か な ？
Can you, can you, can you find me?
あらわる あたし は 行く 先々
I appear everywhere I go
あと 先 ざき なら 考 えない
I don't think about the future
パカパカパ ！ 馬 も びっくり 玉手箱
Clippity-clop! Urashima's casket surprises even horses
手取り 早く トリコ に なれ
Quickly become captivated by me
だって アクスタ だけ じゃ 足り ない でしょ ？
After all, just an acrylic stand isn't enough, right?
一瞬 たりとも 離れ ない が ぶっ ！
I won't leave you for even a moment—chomp!
アイ ら びゅ ポップ ぴゅー
I love you pop you
よそ見 し ない で ね
Don't look away, okay?
愛 あらわ に 結局 は
With love laid bare, in the end
おん りゅ ー じゃん ！
It's only you!
どこそこ どこそこ 分かる か な？
Can you tell where we are?
渋滞まぎれてかなり不安
Getting lost in traffic makes me quite anxious
どこそこ どこそこ 分かる か な？
Can you tell where we are?
どこにいたって君が一番
Wherever we are, you're number one!
ねぇ、遊んで
Hey, let's play
変わる変わる着せ替えごっこ 上下左右アッププのプ
Changing outfits back and forth, up, down, left, right, puff up!
天国地獄お時国 かわいいは作れると猛特訓
Heaven, hell, cuteness can be made, intense training!
ねぇ、いつでも呼んで
Hey, call me anytime,
ついてって360度 遠く遠く夢中ドーク
following you 360 degrees.
アイラブユー ポピー置いてかないでね
I love you, poppy, don't leave me behind!
アイマシマシ抜きのエリータ 踊っだんだんだんだんだんだんだん
More and more love without reason, dance, dance, dance!
アイラブユー ポピー夜更かししないでね
I love you, poppy, don't stay up late!
愛現わに結局はおんりゅーちゃん
Giving you my love, in the end it's only you, chan!
行く先々現るポップな流星 眩しそうこんなリテ ーネ
Appearing wherever we go, a pop meteor, dazzling like this.
ポッケからポピンしのはせ ポピンつー 踏んだり蹴ったりポピン かくれんぼうい
Pop in from the pocket, stealthily pop in 2, step on it, kick it, hide-and-seek boy!
ポッケからポピンしのはせ ポピンつー ぴょん！現るポピンアイドル...
Pop in from the pocket, stealthily pop in 2, boing! The pop-in idol appears...
ポッピン ハッピー トゥー ユー！
Pop in happy to you!
死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんの？
Do you really wanna die as a virgin boy?
Love, bluh bluh bluh
ラブと超ライク パーティションはない、ない
Loving and liking, they're just one and the same
きみだけが特別じゃないんだ
You're not that special, it's just part of the game
反省とか あたしに 求められても… 本当 病んだり勘違いしないでって
“Hey, i’m sorry” – is that really what you want to hear me say?
どうしてなんで期待の戸締り忘れるの？
Stop! Don’t you know, never wanting any more is rule number one?
最初にあれほどやめとけって伝えたじゃん
(I told you) right from the start not to give it any heart
お純情様、あちらが生口ですが…
Mr. commitment, you can find the exit over to the right
やっぱ帰たくない…ですか？
Oh my, are you really staying for the night?
ホップステップ わんまおチャンス！
Hop, step, and one more chance!
もうやっぱアピってラビったらいいじゃん POPな愛撫 誂ったらいいじゃん
So if it’s appeal, keep it real, baby shake that pop in a feel
みっともないから嫉妬仕舞いな 発火しちゃうとかくそだせえな 寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん埋まればいいじゃん
Don’t be a creep, that’s some weird jealousy...
嫌々愛して生きたくなって 死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんの？
Hated to love, but it only gave me life. Are you really gonna die as a virgin boy?
やっぱアピってラビったらいいじゃん BADなダンス 腫れ魔ったらいいじゃん
If it’s appeal, keep it real, baby shake that down with the feels?
やっぱり好きとかやってられんわ 馬鹿じゃない？鳴呼くそ雑魚えわ 寂しくなんたらいつでもいいじゃん埋まればいいじゃん
“Love you!” (I don’t) gross, im going limp, are you out of your mind?
嫌々愛して死にたくなって こっちフラフラやってんの、OK?
I fell in love, and it made me such a bore... OK?
Love, bluh bluh bluh
バーストから インスタントラヴァー 頭＋身体がばかに絡まめあ
Bursting rubber, we’re instant lovers, and under the covers...
ゴーストなら アンデッドマナー 今際未だ淫ら 今際火花散らせそれがアンサー、だ
Ghost's an undead manner...
バーストから インスタントラヴァー 頭＋身体がばかに絡まめあ
Bursting rubber, we’re instant lovers...
ゴーストなら アンデッドマナー 今際未だ淫ら 今際火花散らせそれがアンサー、だ
Ghost's an undead manner...
ホップステップ わんまおチャンス！もうやっぱアピってラビったらいいじゃん
Hop step one more chance!
みっともないから嫉妬仕舞いな… 寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん埋まればいいじゃん
Don't be a creep...
嫌々愛して生きたくなって 死ぬまでピュアピュアやってんの？
Hated to love...
やっぱアピってラビったらいいじゃん...
If it's appeal...
嫌々愛して死にたくなって こっちフラフラやってんの
I fell in love...
やっぱアピってラビったらいいじゃん トップの塔に追われ思い出し みっともないとか言ってごめんね 発火したいけどもうだめなんだ 寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん埋まればいいじゃん
If it's appeal...
否々愛して逝きたくなって こっちフラフラやってんの、OK?
Refusing to love...
ややややや悪い子さん ままままあお愛しこじょん さっさっさっ始めるよ もっとこの愛してよ
My my my, you're just a little freak...
さっさっさっ始めるよ もっとこの愛してよ
Start the show...
交わしたはずのない約束が
Promises that shouldn't have been exchanged
今日も 僕らの未来を奪おうとする
will try and take away our future today, too.
欲しかったものを手に入れても
Even if I obtain what I wanted,
素直に うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
I wonder why I still can't smile naturally.
あふれる涙は 弱さや後悔じゃない
These overflowing tears are neither weakness nor regret,
イタミが産んだカケラで
but fragments born from the pain.
どんな瞬間だって 運命だって
Whatever moment, whatever fate,
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that only one thing is certain.
ひとりで考えちゃって 現実を迷うより
Rather than getting lost in reality thinking all alone,
明日を 迎えにいくだ
I'm going to go greet tomorrow!
ずっと持っていたい 心の地雷 スイッチは切ってない
I always want to keep the landmine switch of my heart unclicked.
いつも僕を見てる ありふれたメロディが
The familiar melody that always watches over me
くだらないと人に笑われても
even if people laugh at it as worthless,
キラキラ なおさら輝くのはなぜだろう
shines even brighter—I wonder why.
何が真実で嘘か リクツじゃなくて
Not by logic of what is truth or a lie,
感じていたい ココロで
but with my heart, I want to feel it.
きっと愛情なんて 幻想だって
Surely love is an illusion,
ごまかしたくないよ 傷ついたと
I don't want to fake it, even if I got hurt.
知っても 分かち合いたいと強く願うほど
The more strongly I wish to share and understand,
ぶつかる こともあるから
the more we might also clash.
泣けるくらい 青空 交差点で 手を伸ばした
Under a blue sky that makes you want to cry, I reached out my hand at the intersection.
10年後も こんなふうにいられるかな 一緒に
I wonder if we can still be like this 10 years from now, together.
どんな瞬間だって 運命だって
Whatever moment, whatever fate,
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that only one thing is certain.
限界だって 困難だって あきらめたくないよ
No matter the limits or hardships, I don't want to give up.
このまま 離さないで
Don't let go of me just like this;
硬く握り締めた 君の右手ぬくもり
the warmth of your right hand that I tightly grasped
ここにあるから
is still right here with me.
はーい、ということで 4曲連続で聞いていただきましたー！
Haai, and with that, you've listened to four songs in a row!
どうでしたでしょうか？
How was it?
結構ね、スバルの好きな曲とかやりたいことをですね、こうギュッと詰め込んだパートになっております。
It's a segment packed tightly with songs Subaru loves and things I wanted to do!
えー、ここからですね、いよいよね、ライブも終盤ということで！
Uh, from here, the live concert is finally reaching its final stage!
えー、ここからはなんとちょっとみんなに告知があります！うれしいお知らせです。
Uh, from here, I actually have an announcement for everyone! A happy notice.
なんと、大空スバル 6周年記念ライブのグッズ告知でーす！
It's the goods announcement for Oozora Subaru's 6th Anniversary Live!
それではこちらをどうぞ！
So please take a look at this!
来たーー！ということで、今回ももりだくさんのグッズをご紹介していきたいと思います！
Here it comes! And so, I'd like to introduce a lot of merchandise this time as well!
今回のイラストは、しぐれうい先生に描いていただきました！うい先生、いつもありがとうございます！
This time's illustrations were drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei! Ui-sensei, thank you as always!
今回のグッズはマネージャー応援がコンセプトとなっています。早速見ていきましょう！まずは、こちら！
The concept of this merchandise is "Manager Support." Let's take a look right away! First, this one!
スバルがおうえん！！BIGアクリルスタンド！
Subaru's Cheering!! BIG Acrylic Stand!
スバルがみんなを応援しているイラストのBIGなアクリル…
A big acrylic stand featuring an illustration of Subaru cheering everyone on...
スタンドです！
It's a stand!
スバルに応援されたい人にぴったりの存在感抜群な商品となっております！
Designed with great presence, perfect for anyone who wants Subaru's support!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
スバルがおうえん!! ボイスキーホルダー！
Subaru's Cheering Voice Keychain!
全6種類のボイスがランダムに再生されるボイスキーホルダーです！
A voice keychain that plays 6 random voice lines!
応援ボイスなどもりだくさんですので、ぜひみんないっぱい聴いてみてください！
Packed with cheering voices, so everyone please listen lots!
こちらのイラストはごまのりお先生に描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This illustration was drawn by Gomanorio-sensei! Thank you!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next up is this!
スバルのストップウォッチ風コインケース！
Subaru's Stopwatch-style Coin Case!
こちらはですね、通常衣装のストップウォッチをイメージしたコインケースになっております！
This coin case is styled after her default outfit's stopwatch!
普段使いしやすい商品ですのでぜひみんなも使ってみてください！
It's easy for daily use, so everyone please try using it!
さあ、まだまだありますよ！
Now, there's still more!
続いては、こちら！スバルのマネージャーノート！
Next is this! Subaru's Manager Notebook!
こちらはですね、マネージャーモードのスバルが普段使っているマネージャーノートになっております！
This is the manager notebook Subaru usually uses in manager mode!
あと普段はですね、RPGの実況なんかの時も使っています。
She also uses it during RPG let's-plays.
ということで、こちらも普段使いしやすいので、皆さんぜひチェックしてみてください！
So this is also great for everyday use, be sure to check it out!
そして、フルセット購入特典もあります！こちらどうぞ！
And there's also a full-set purchase bonus! Here it is!
箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードとなっておりますので、ぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
It's a cheki-style bromide card with a foil-stamped replica signature, check it out!
はい、ということで改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！
So, here is the full set once again!
ぜひスバルにいっぱい応援されたいよという方はチェックしてみてください！
If you want lots of support from Subaru, be sure to check it out!
そして、さらにお知らせがあります！なんだって？こちらをご覧ください！
And there's more news! What is it? Take a look at this!
なんと！大空スバル1stアルバム『Pleiades』が3月3日に発売となります！やったー！
Oozora Subaru's 1st album 'Pleiades' will be released on March 3rd! Yay!
こちらのアルバムはですね、今まで出してきたスバルの思い出いっぱいの曲を1つのアルバムにぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅっと詰め込みました！
This album packs all of Subaru's memorable songs released so far into one!
このあと披露する2曲の新曲や、いろんなホロメンに参加してもらった大空警察の曲まで！10曲がですね、ぎゅっと詰まったアルバムになっております！ぜひいっぱい聴いてください！
Including two new songs to be shown later and Oozora Police featuring various holomem! 10 songs packed tightly! Please listen a lot!
特典もですね、6種類のランダムトレーディングカードやメッセージカード、そして今回のですね、このライブのダイジェストMV視聴カードなどもりだくさんですので、ぜひぜひぜひ買ってきてみてください！よろしくお願いします！買って買って買って買って！
The bonuses include 6 random trading cards, message cards, and a digest MV viewing card of this live! So please buy it! Please, please, please buy it!
ということで以上、大空スバル6周年記念ライブのグッズ情報とアルバム情報でした！みんないっぱい買ってくださーい！よろしくお願いします！
That's all for the merch and album info for Subaru's 6th anniversary live! Everyone please buy lots! Thank you!
はい！そしてなんと、いよいよライブも終盤戦ということで！
Yes! And now, the live is finally reaching its final stretch!
それでは、次の曲のチャンピオンへ！それでは聴いてください！
Now, to the champion of the next song! Please listen!
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The season of blue that seemed to go on forever,
四つ並ぶ窓この前を塞ぐものは何もない
Four lined-up windows, nothing blocks what's ahead.
アスファルトと蝉時雨を反射して
Reflecting the asphalt and the chorus of cicadas,
君という沈黙が聞こえなくなる
I can no longer hear the silence called you.
この日々が色褪せる僕と違う君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if these days fade, and I learn a scent different from yours,
置き忘れてきた永遠のそこに
In that eternity we left behind,
今でも青が住んでいる
The blue still lives there,
The blue still lives there.
どんな祈りも言葉も近づけるのに届かなかった
No matter how close prayers and words got, they couldn't reach.
まるで仕掛けた恋のような魔法だった夏のようないろのなか
Like a set-up romance, it was magic amidst colors like summer.
切り落とす言葉がずっと喉の奥に仕えているまた会えるよねって
Words to cut off are stuck deep in my throat— 'We'll meet again, right?'
声にならない声
A voice that cannot become a voice.
眠る下がりじめつく風の季節は
The season of wind clinging as we sleep,
思い出すまだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
Reminds me of our portraits when we were still nobodies.
何もかもも分かり合えたはずだった
We must have understood everything about each other.
あの日から少しずつ君と違う僕という呪いが解けていく
Ever since that day, little by little, the curse of being myself, different from you, lifts.
君の笑顔の奥の憂いも
Even the sorrow deep within your smile,
身を閉した孤独や見尽くして
And the closed-off loneliness, seeing through them all...
Starlight
繋いで 繰り返してく衝動
Connecting them, repeating impulses.
僕らは止まらない きらり 輝いてゆけ
We can't stop, shining brightly.
地を蹴った足取りは 弾んだリズムで
With the rhythm of our stepping feet,
キミの心の壁を また奏らす
repeating the echoes in your heart.
光線となって やがて形作ったキャンバスの上
Light becomes a beam, eventually forming a canvas.
灯る道 満開 星屑
A shining path to light our way,
迷いはしない また前を向けるから
I will never lose my way, facing forward once again.
Fly again 飛ぶんだ
Fly again, let's fly away.
導かれたこの舞台 いつか聞こえる日まで
This stage that guided us will someday reach the day we hear it.
空高く掲げた 手を重ね
Lifting our hands high into the sky, stacking them together,
ぶっこわした限界の その先へ
breaking past the limits and heading beyond!
思わず涙が こぼれ落ちそうな そんな夜には
Tears threaten to spill over on such a night,
連れてくよ さあ 一緒に 夜空に差し込む
let's take a journey together, stealing into the night sky.
きらめくスターライト いつでも届けたい
Sparkling starlight, I always want to reach you,
笑顔になる歌があるから
because there is a song that will make you smile.
Be the star 歌おう 一面 染まる金世界
Be the star, let's sing across a stained golden world,
今も まだ焼き付いて
where it is still vividly burned into my mind.
空高く響いた 激情 まだ最高潮
Soaring high, echoing with a passion that reaches a new peak,
昨日よりも翔けるんだ 遠くまで
let's reach even further than yesterday!
Fly again 飛ぶんだ
Fly again, let's fly away,
指先触れた 結晶
with the crystal that brushed our fingertips.
Be the star なるんだ キミの一等星
Be the star, let's become your guiding first-magnitude star!
Starlight 輝け 僕らは いつだってここにいるよ
Starlight, shine on! We will always be right here,
願いよ届け
so please let our wishes reach you.
無限の宇宙を 流れる星となって
Flowing like shooting stars through the infinite cosmos,
キミと僕ら照らす その先へ
illuminating both you and me, heading towards that future,
超えて 超えて
pushing past everything...
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ傷つけて傷ついたって
No matter how far we run through, even if we get hurt,
明日は笑っていたいな
Tomorrow, I want to be smiling.
間違いもいつかのための正解でしょ
Even mistakes will someday be the right answer, right?
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃんさあ行くんだ
Falling down, crying, being clumsy is fine, so let's go!
色褪せたこの世界で繰り返していくだけの毎日
In this fading world, living days repeating over and over,
言えずにいた言葉を風に乗せて一人呟いた
I whispered the words I couldn't say into the wind.
素直になるためにはまだまだ勇気が足りないけど
To become honest, I still don't have enough courage, but
水しぶき上げて飛び込んだ目をつぶりながら
closing my eyes, I splashed and jumped in!
悪天候に虹を描いて青く塗りつぶした
Drawing a rainbow in bad weather, painting it blue,
扉開けて飛び出そうよはじめての未来へ
Breaking the door open, let's fly out to our first future!
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ傷つけて傷ついたって
No matter how far we run through, even if we get hurt,
明日は笑っていたいな
Tomorrow, I want to be smiling.
間違いもいつかのための正解でしょ
Even mistakes will someday be the right answer, right?
顔上げて走り出そうひとりぼっちがふたりで
With my head held high, let's start running—just the two of us!
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃんさあ行くんだ
Falling down, crying, being clumsy is fine, so let's go!
何が正解で不正解かもときどきわからなくなって
What is right and what is wrong, sometimes I don't even know,
涙こらえながら答えを探し続けてたんだ
holding back tears, I kept searching for the answer.
溢れた涙見つけた笑顔全部宝箱にしまって
Put all the overflowing tears and found smiles into a treasure chest,
いつか立ち止まったら思い出してまた笑いたいな
so that whenever I stop, I can remember and smile again.
満天の星空を描いて願い事をしよう
Drawing a starry sky as far as the eye can see, let's make a wish!
流れ星も描き足そうか僕次第で変わるんだ
Drawing shooting stars, can we make them come true? It depends on us!
いつまでもこの日々が続くといいな
I hope these days last forever.
望んだって叶わないことだらけでも悪くないな
Even if most of my wishes don't come true, that's not so bad.
明日へとこの歌が届くといいな
I hope this song reaches tomorrow too,
手を取って笑い合ってありのままを描いていくんだ
taking hands and laughing together, let's paint our true selves!
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ傷つけて傷ついたって
No matter how far we run through, even if we get hurt,
明日は笑っていたいな
Tomorrow, I want to be smiling.
間違いもいつかのための正解だから
Even mistakes will someday be the right answer, right?
顔上げて走り出そうひとりぼっちがふたりで
With my head held high, let's start running—just the two of us!
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃんさあ行くんだ
Falling down, crying, being clumsy is fine, so let's go!
どこまでも駆け抜けていくんだ
No matter how far we run through!
君とスバルの未来が幸せでいっぱいでありますように!!
May your future with Subaru be full of happiness!!